SYED SHOYEB

Associate Consultant

Email: syedshoyeb1@gmail.com Mobile No: (+91) – 7013122662

#### **Career Objective:**

Software developer with proven experience in developing real-time, database and web-based products in various sectors. I successfully contributed my skills in long-term projects in completion as well as rapid problem-solving demands.

#### **Professional Summary**

3.7 years of IT-experience, extensively in development of web-based Applications using Java, J2EE, Spring MVC, Spring core and Spring batch

Good development experience in developing Restful services using spring boot.

Working experience in Tomcat and Web Application servers.

Experience in web applications development on IDEs like Eclipse, Spring Tool Suite, Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code.

Worked on MySQL Workbench and TOAD tool.

Knowledge and work experience in using **Bitbucket**, **Bamboo**, **Urban Code Deployment**, **and Service Now**.

Excellent troubleshooting, analytical and communication skills.

Highly flexible and passionate of learning new tools/frameworks for high-end application /development.

# **Technical Skills:**

Java Technologies : Java, J2EE, Restful Web Services

Frameworks : Spring MVC, Spring Batch and Spring Core IDE Tool : Eclipse, Spring Tool suite and Visual Code.

**Versioning Tools** : Bit Bucket and UCD.

Ticket System : Service Now

Web Server : Apache-Tomcat 7.0,8.0, Web

application server

**Operating Systems**: Windows

**Database** : TOAD ,MySQL Workbench

# **Work Experience:**

- Working as Associate Consultant, with Cappemini Technology Services India Limited from Feb 2019 to till date
- O Worked as Software Analyst with Bayhub Groups Pvt Ltd from Mar 2018 to Jan 2019

### **Education Qualification:**

O Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering(CSE) from KSRM College of Engineering '2017

# **Projects:**

Project 1 : MetCheck
Client : Metlife

Platform : Spring batch, Spring core, Spring boot

Workplace : CAPGEMINI

Duration : Jan' 2020 to till date

**Description**: MetCheck is a check processing system which get feeds from Admin system.

Application loads the check data in the batch flow as well as manual data entry flow into the database and the check data extracted and sent to print site to print the checks. Application will act like stub repository to verify various check status and also has down streams like TAX, Reconciliation etc.

# **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Analysing and Developing batch flows for a line of business.
- Implementing the requirements as per the business requirements.
- O Preparing Functional requirement document and Technical designing documents.
- Implementing UI enhancements.
- Involved in application testing and defect fixing.
- O Doing DEV and UAT deployment into servers and fixing issues occurred in UAT.
- Giving support in PRODUCTION deployments and involved immediate issue fix after deployment.

Project 2 : Provida

Client : MetLifeMexico
Platform : PL/SQL, Oracle
Workplace : CAPGEMINI

Duration : Feb' 2019 to Jan' 2020

Description : PROVIDA is basically a policy administration system in MetLife Mexico that offers individual life insurance policies. PROVIDA Maintenance basically deals with the backend operations. Policy owner request MLM for issuance or some changes in policy which are to be applied in system. This is done using PIP screen which internally calls PROVIDA application and other related modules like Personal Repository, Financial module etc.

# **Roles and Responsibilities:**

O Involved in all phases of the SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle) from design

• Development, testing, implementation and maintenance with timely delivery against aggressive deadlines.

O Involved in development and modification of complex database objects like Stored Procedures, Functions, Packages using SQL and PL/SQL.

Project 3 : CapStore-Online Retail Marketplace

Platform : Java, J2EE-Spring MVC, JSP, JavaScript and Oracle

Workplace : Bayhub Groups

Duration : Mar 2018 to Jan 2019.

**Description** : CapStore-Online Retail Marketplace is an Online application used to sell different varieties of goods. Merchants can sell their products to customers who can view them, and buy them

### **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- O Used Spring Data JPA to do the retrieval of cart items from the Database.
- O Involved in development of user modules.
- O Developed client-side validations for all user modules.
- Involved in application testing and defect fixing in testing phase.